0

Mohammed AlJaser

aljaser717@gmail.com



Open to Relocation



OVERVIEW

GitHub | LinkedIn

Certified .Net Developer with three years' experience in Software Engineering and Web Development. Expertise in C#, .Net MVC, jQuery, SQL, and other technologies. Well-versed in implementations, gathering business requirements, and developing solutions. In search of a new software engineering role with a company that values hard work and success.

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- Improved unit test coverage from 0 percent to 30 percent following TDD method.
- Develop Entity Framework and made LINQ queries to connect to the database and implemented CRUD functionality with Entity Framework Database First and Code First approaches with ASP.NET MVC.
- Maintain and develop applications based on business requirements using C# .Net MVC, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree: Software Engineering Robert Morris University Dec 2016

Dean's List – Spring 15, Summer 15, Fall 15, Spring 16

Software Engineering Award 2015-16 Academic Year

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Operating Systems: Windows, Mac, Linux

<u>Programming Languages:</u> C#, C#.Net, Python, Java, HTML, T-SQL, PL/SQL, Go, Kotlin, Swift, Ruby

<u>Web Technologies:</u> Html, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Kendo UI, XML, React, Redux, Dart <u>IDE:</u> Visual Studio, SQL Server Management Studio, Xamarin, Android Studio, XCode, Visual Code

<u>Frameworks:</u> .Net, .Net MVC, .Net Core, NodeJS, Express JS Angular, Entity Framework, Rails, Xamarin

Databases: SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL, Mongo

Reporting Tool: SQL Server Reporting Services, Crystal Reports

<u>Version Control Tools:</u> Team Foundation Server, GIT, GitHub, GitLab, Azure DevOps

Middleware: WPF, WCF, ADO.NET, Web API, Web Services, LINQ Project Management: Microsoft Project, Target Process, Jira Self-Taught: Python, React, Angular, NodeJS, Kotlin, Swift, Xamarin

KNOWLEDGE AREAS:

OOP

HIPPA Compliance Web Development

Project Management Linear Programming

Application Development

Business Requirements

System Optimization

Large Scale Designs

Code Verification

SDLC

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Five Lakes Dental Practice Solutions | Cleveland, OH | SEP 2017 - PRESENT

- Increased unit test coverage to 30% across all applications.
- Mentored recent graduate employees on development functions.
- Maintain existing applications and develop new applications based on business requirements using C#.Net MVC, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Ajax.
- $\bullet \qquad \hbox{Responsible for all phases of the software development lifecycle.}$
- Apply best design patterns such as n-tier, MVVM, Repository, and Singleton for designing key reusable components.
- Implement and gather the business requirement using Kanban development process.
- Apply Multithreading techniques for creating high performance applications.
- Develop Stored Procedures, Views, Functions, Queries using SQL Server.
- Create Html Helpers to reduce the amount of tedious typing of HTML tags.
- Develop Entity Framework and made LINQ queries to connect to the database and implemented CRUD functionality with Entity Framework Database First and Code First approaches with ASP.NET MVC.
- Sit the Azure DevOps formerly TFS for CI/CDS build on OA and UAT environment.
- Used Azure DevOps formerly TFS as our version control.

Software Engineer

eSource Technology | Pittsburgh, PA | JAN 2017 - SEP 2017

- Developed solutions for diverse programming scenarios in C#.Net, Implemented Object Oriented Programming (OOP) concepts such as encapsulation, inheritance, polymorphism, and abstraction.
- Implementations:
 - View, Model, Controller and View model by using ASP.Net MVC Framework.
 - UI layer using Partial views, views, Layouts, Themes by using Razor, Bootstrap, HTML5.
- Used ASP.NET MVC Page Controller pattern to add functionality to individual pages such that to accept input from the page request invoke the requested actions on the mode.

CERTIFICATIONS

.NET Framework 4.0 Brainbench JULY 2017